HITESH SAPRA

TEAM LEAD | TPM | MOBILE ENGINEER & FULL-STACK | API & CLOUD INTEGRATION EXPERT

Kuwait City | (+965) 96778587 | saprahits007@gmail.com | [in] hiteshsapra | [Web] hiteshsapra

SUMMARY

Experienced Team Lead/TPM and Software Engineer with 9+ years in mobile (Flutter, Android, iOS), backend (Python/Django, PHP, APIs), web (TypeScript, Next.js, Vue.js), cloud (AWS, Firebase), IDEs (Android Studio, Xcode, PyCharm, VS Code), tools (Jira, Trello, Confluence, Anasa, etc.), micro-architecture design, Figma UI/UX, payment gateway integrations, version control (Git, GitHub, Bitbucket), and project management.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Leadership & Communication
- Business Analysis & UI/UX (Figma)
- Project Management
 Problem Solving

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Cloud & Micro-Architecture
- REST API, GraphQL, OAuth2
- CI/CD & Version
 Control
- Databases Design

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Team Lead/TPM, CodeFusion Bit LLP, Rajkot

May 2023 - Present

 Mobile Team Lead & TPM: led teams (Kuwait City), developer, design docs, client talks, estimation, analysis.

Team Lead, 9series Solutions Pvt. Ltd. (Ahmedabad, Gujarat)

March 2022 -May-2024

• Mobile Team Lead: team mgmt, developer, DB design, client talks, estimates, POCs, microarchitecture.

Sr. Android and Flutter Developer, Bito1 Techplode (Ahmedabad, Gujarat) Feb 2019 - March 2022

• Sr. Android & Flutter Dev, Team Lead: app development, team mgmt, delivery ownership.

Android and Web Developer, Appeters Technology (Rajkot, Gujarat)

Jan 2016 - Feb 2019

PHP Web Developer & Android Developer: web backend & mobile app development tasks.

HIGHLIGHTED PROJECTS

(55+ TOTAL PROJECTS COMPLETED)

Education Mobile and Web Application (Current Project)

March 2024 - Present

• Implement a cross-platform mobile and web solution using Flutter (Dart) and TypeScript to streamline student lifecycle management and provide robust administrative reporting capabilities.

Fitness App

May 2023 -March-2024

• Flutter/Dart mobile app for Online bookings; video player via method channel, workout tracking (Kalman, pedometer), dynamic booking layout.

EDUCATION

Master of Computer Application(MCA)

June 2016 - May 2018

Gujarat Technological University, India.

• Gained strong foundation in full-stack development, backend architecture, and business analysis.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Languages: English, Hindi, Gujarati...
- Integrations Expertise: 55+ projects with Payment Gateway (PayPal, Stripe, and many more) and Third-Party API Integration (AWS, Firebase, Contentful API, OpenCV, Kalman Filter, Auth0, OAuth2, Pedometer, Apple Watch, Network Screen Casting).
- Activities: Experience in client communication, team leadership, project estimation, and business analysis with international clients (UK, USA, Kuwait and India).